Guide to the Donald Jay Grout papers,1929-2002.
Grout, Donald Jay papers
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence - Primarily from period of Grout's retirement (1970-1987)and following his death
    - Grove Dictionary, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Guerlac, Henry, 1978-1985 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Guzman, Jose Manuel Garrido, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - H. misc., 1968-1979 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - H and Z, misc. correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Hall, Bob, 1975-1985 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Halsey, Steven and Harriet, 1989-1991 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Hamilton, Harry S. (Attorney in Ithaca), 1985 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Hansell, Sven, 1973-1976 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Hardie, Graham and Jane, 1971-1977 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Hardwick, Lester C., 1982 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Hattori, Prof. Dr. Kozo, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Harvard University Press, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Harvard Visiting Committee, 1974-1979 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Heartz, Daniel, 1969-1980 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Heritage of Music (Alan Kendall), 1981 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Hilton, Mrs. Ruth, 1978-1980 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Hsu, John, 1972-1991 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Hughes, David and Betty, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Hunter, Mary (Parakilas), 1975-1978 (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Hutchins, Bernard, 1967-1970 (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - IMS, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - IMS, 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - IMS RISM, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - IMS Congress Strasbourg, August 29, 1982 - September 3, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Inamori Foundation, Japan, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - Internationales Quellenlexikon der Musik, 1975-1981 (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Internationales Quellenlexikon der Musik, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - Ithaca Property, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - J. misc. correspondence, 1967-1976 (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Jacobs, Charles, 1968-1983 (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - Jenkins, Newell, 1975-1979 (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - K. misc. correspondence, 1961-1979 (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - Kansas, September 1977-1978 (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - Keller, Michael A., 1975-1983 (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - Kennedy, Irving H., 1981 (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - Kerman, Joseph, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 42)
    - Kiefer, Jack, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 43)
    - King, Alexander Hyatt, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 44)
    - Kirkendale, Ursula, 1969-1976 (Box 53, Folder 45)
    - Kirkpatrick, Mary P., 1974-1981 (Box 53, Folder 46)
    - Kirkpatrick Family, 1981-1991 (Box 53, Folder 47)
    - Knowlton, Edgar C. Jr., 1968-1985 (Box 53, Folder 48)
    - Koninklijke Academie voor Wetenschappen, Letteren en Schone Kunsten van België, 1971-1987 (Box 53, Folder 49)
    - L misc. correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 53, Folder 50)
    - Lang, Paul Henry, 1969-1989 (Box 53, Folder 51)
    - Lang, Paul Henry, 1968-1982 (Box 53, Folder 52)
    - Lamb, Hubert W., 1977-1989 (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - LaRue, Jan, 1967-1986 (Box 53, Folder 54)
    - Lazarevich, Gordana, 1973-1975 (Box 53, Folder 55)
    - Leahy, Eugene, 1970-1978 (Box 53, Folder 56)
    - Lenaerts, René B., 1977-1986 (Box 53, Folder 57)
    - Letters of Appreciation, 1970-1983 (Box 53, Folder 58)
    - Levin, Monroe, 1971-1982 (Box 53, Folder 59)
    - Levy, Kenneth (Princeton), 1972 (Box 53, Folder 60)
    - Lippmann, Friedrich, 1969-1976 (Box 53, Folder 61)
    - Longyear, Rey M., 1977-1982 (Box 53, Folder 62)
    - Longyear, Rey M., 1982-1991 (Box 53, Folder 63)
    - Lowinsky, Edward, 1961-1979 (Box 53, Folder 64)
    - M misc. correspondence, 1964-1982 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Mc misc. correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - McGuinness, Rosamond "Corky", 1968-1983 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Meikle, Bob, 1967-1976 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Melbourne, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Memorial statement, 1987 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Cornell memorial statements, 1986-1987 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Merritt, Tillman, 1981-1985 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Mintz, Donald, 1970-1978 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Moe, Larry, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Mohr, Ernst, 1975-1979 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Moroney, Davitt, 1976-1977 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Morrison, Toni; pupil of Donald Jay Grout (clipping) (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Mozarteum, 1976-2002 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - N misc. correspondence, 1968-1978 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - N. E. H. (National Endowment for the Humanities), 1968-1970 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - New Berlioz edition, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - N. Y. Federation of Music Clubs award and correspondence, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - O misc. correspondence, 1956-1977 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Old letters, 1926-1934 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Owlett, Carolyn (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - P misc. correspondence, 1968-1985 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Palisca, Claude, 1967-1983 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Paterson, Don, 1970-1980 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - Petrobelli, Pierluigi, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - Petty, Fred C., 1969-1978 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - Pirrotta, Nino, 1969-1983 (Box 54, Folder 26)
    - Poland, 1976-1986 (Box 54, Folder 27)
    - Q misc., correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - R misc., correspondence, 1971-1981 (Box 54, Folder 29)
    - Randel, Don, correspondence, 1969-1978 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Reeser, Henk and Christine, correspondence, 1981-1988 (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Reeser, Eduard (Henk), Netherlands, correspondence, 1968-1986 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - Rehm, Wolfgang, correspondence, 1969-1983 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Reiner, Stuart, correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 54, Folder 34)
    - RISM, letter, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - RISM - Libretto Project, 1981-1986 (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, Inc., correspondence (Box 54, Folder 37)
    - Rokahr, Jack correspondence, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - Rosenblum, Myron correspondence, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 39)
    - Rosen, Charles, correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 54, Folder 40)
    - Rösing, Helmut, correspondence, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 41)
    - Rostirolla, Giancarlo, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 54, Folder 42)
    - R. M. A. (Royal Musical Association) Review, correspondence, 1977 (Box 54, Folder 43)
    - Rutgers, correspondence, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 44)
    - S misc., correspondence, 1968-1984 (Box 54, Folder 45)
    - Sadie, Stanley, 1972-1985 (Box 54, Folder 46)
    - Samuel, Harold, 1968-1991 (Box 54, Folder 47)
    - Sartori, Claudio, 1966-1976 (Box 54, Folder 48)
    - Schiller, Jonathan, 1971-1982 (Box 54, Folder 49)
    - Schmidt, Carl B., 191977-1978 (Box 54, Folder 50)
    - Shotwell, Louisa, 1974-1986 (Box 54, Folder 51)
    - Skaneateles Festival, Friends of, 1981-1983 (Box 54, Folder 52)
    - Skaneateles history, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 53)
    - Smither, Howard Elbert, 1967-1978 (Box 54, Folder 54)
    - Statler Club, 1981-1985 (Box 54, Folder 55)
    - Stevens, Denis, 1966-1981 (Box 54, Folder 56)
    - Strunk, Oliver, 1969-1980 (Box 54, Folder 57)
    - T misc. correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 54, Folder 58)
    - Tangeman, Clementine, 1964-1988 (Box 54, Folder 59)
    - Tolley, William, 1969-1995 (Box 54, Folder 60)
    - Traub, Warren F., 1971-1982 (Box 54, Folder 61)
    - Troxell, Barbara, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 62)
    - University of California at Berkeley, Faculty Club, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 63)
    - University of Louisville, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 64)
    - Parma/Palermo Universities (Italy), 1980-1986 (Box 54, Folder 65)
    - V misc. correspondence, 1968-1983 (Box 54, Folder 66)
    - van Marken, Henri, 1978-1979 (Box 54, Folder 67)
    - Vaughan Williams, Ursula, 1968-1989 (Box 54, Folder 68)
    - Vente, Maarten Albert, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 69)
    - Vermont Institute of Community Involvement, 1975-1976 (Box 54, Folder 70)
    - Vogel-Garrett, Edith, 1971-1976 (Box 54, Folder 71)
    - W misc. correspondence, 1967-1986 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Waterman, George, 1970-1979 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Wildberger, Melvin (music engraver), 1975-1979 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Williams, Hermine, 1981-1991 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Wiora, Walter, 1967-1976 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Wolff, Hellmuth Christian, 1967-1978 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Woodworth Family Newsletter, 1984-1999 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Woodworth, G. Wallace, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Woodward, Henry and Enid, 1978-1990 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Zaslaw, Neal, 1971-1982 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - XYZ misc. correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Norton contracts (copies), 1953-1985 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - W.W. Norton, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - W.W. Norton, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - W.W. Norton, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - W.W. Norton, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - W.W. Norton, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - W.W. Norton, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - W.W. Norton, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - W.W. Norton, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - W.W. Norton, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - W.W. Norton, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - W.W. Norton, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - W.W. Norton, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - W.W. Norton, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - W.W. Norton, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - W.W. Norton, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - W.W. Norton, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - W.W. Norton, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - W.W. Norton, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - W.W. Norton, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - W.W. Norton, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - W.W. Norton, 1967 (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - W.W. Norton, 1966 (Box 55, Folder 34)
    - W.W. Norton, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - W.W. Norton, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 36)
    - W.W. Norton, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 37)
    - W.W. Norton, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 38)
    - W.W. Norton, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 39)
    - W.W. Norton, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 40)
    - W.W. Norton, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 41)
    - W.W. Norton, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 42)
    - W.W. Norton, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 43)
    - W.W. Norton, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 44)
    - W.W. Norton, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 45)
    - W.W. Norton, 1954 (Box 55, Folder 46)
    - W.W. Norton, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 47)
    - W.W. Norton, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 48)
    - W.W. Norton, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 49)
    - W.W. Norton, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 50)
    - W.W. Norton (Grout Vita and HWM promotional materials), 1960-1982 (Box 55, Folder 51)
    - W.W. Norton (reader comments, HWM 3rd edition), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 52)
    - W.W. Norton (letters to/from Margaret Dunn Grout), 1988 (Box 55, Folder 53)
    - W.W. Norton (letters from Steven Swerdfeger and Margaret Dunn Grout), 1988-1990 (Box 55, Folder 54)
    - International Institute for Comparative Music Studies and Documentation, 1970-1978 (Box 55, Folder 55)
    - International Institute for Comparative Music Studies and Documentation, 1979-1983 (Box 55, Folder 56)
- Series II. Short History of Opera
  - Correspondence
    Related to first and second editions
    - Correspondence, January - May 1943 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, June - December 1943 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1946 - 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1947 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1959 - 1961 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1960 - 1963 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1962 - 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Columbia University Press
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 88)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 89)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press Contracts, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 90)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 91)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 92)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 93)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1964-1965 (Box 56, Folder 94)
    - Short History of Opera: Columbia University Press, 1966-1974 (Box 56, Folder 95)
    - ASHOO Reviews, 2nd edition, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 96)
  - Notes and other items
    Related to opera, opéra comique, the music of Gherardi, Molière's comedie-ballets, vaudevilles, parodies, musical examples, and a manuscript copy of Grout's doctoral thesis on opéra comique.
    - notebook: Music 33 opéra comique, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - notebook: Opéra comique, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - notebook: Origins of opéra comique, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - notebook: Music 33 opéra comique, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - notebook: Vaudevilles and parodies, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - notebook: Origins of opéra comique - abstract of thesis, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - notebook: The Fair Theatres, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - notebook: Italian comedies, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - notebook: The Vaudeville, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - notes on the music in the Gherardi plays, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - thesis manuscript, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - notes on early opéra comique, 1936 - 1941 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - notes on Molière's comédie-ballets, 1937 - 1942 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - two loose sheets of paper: opéra comique, LC card numbers, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - notes with music examples, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - list of parodies in early opéra comique 1939 Supplement I, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Gherardi music Supplement II, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - notebook on opera, Strasbourg, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - notebook on opera, Strasbourg, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - typed bibliography, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - bibliography cards, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Work sheets for first edition
    - work copies of music, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - work copies of music, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - work copies of music, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - work copies of music, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 1-8, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 9-13, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 14 and 15, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 16-19, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 20-23, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Chapters 24-26, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 27 and 28, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bibliography 652-750, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Bibliography 751-850, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Bibliography 851-end, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Music examples 1-15, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Music examples 16-31, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Music examples 32-54, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Music examples 55-70, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Music examples 71-90, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Music examples 91-105, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Music examples 106-127, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Work sheets for second edition
    - pages 1-47, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - pages 48-83, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - pages 84-105, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - pages 106-132, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - pages 133-164, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - pages 165-207, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - pages 208-246, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - pages 247-274, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - pages 275-323, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - pages 324-356, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - pages 357-407, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - pages 408-452, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - pages 463-496, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - pages 499-536, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 26, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 27, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Instructions, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Extra proposed pages 1-47, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Notes on twentieth century opera, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Notes on twentieth century opera, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Notes on operas heard May-August 1960, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Permission data, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Old and revised examples; translations of new examples, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Sources of new music examples, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Printer's copy and material related to the publications
    - Chapters 1-4, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Chapters 5-8, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Chapters 9-12, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Chapters 13-14, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Chapters 15-16, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Chapters 17-18, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Chapters 19-20, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Chapters 22-23, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Chapters 24-25, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 26, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 27; prefaces to first and second editions, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Music examples 5135-5180, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Music examples 5181-5220, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Music examples 5221-5260, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Music examples 5261-5295, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Music examples 5261-5295, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Proofread copy with changes
    - New examples; data sheets, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Part I, chapter 1, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Part I, chapter 2, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Part I, chapter 3, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Part I, chapter 4, retyped, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Part I, chapter 4, rejected pages, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Part II, chapter 5, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Part II, chapter 6, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Part II, chapter 7, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Part II, chapter 8, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Part II, chapter 9, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Part II, chapter 10, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Part II, chapter 11, changes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Part II, chapter 12, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Part III, chapter 13, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Part III, chapter 14, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Part III, chapter 15, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Part III, chapter 16, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Part III, chapter 17, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Part IV, chapter 18, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Part IV, chapter 19, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Part IV, chapter 20, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Part IV, chapter 21, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Part IV, chapter 22, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Part IV, chapter 23, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Part IV, chapter 24, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Part IV, chapter 25, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Part V, chapter 26, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Part V, chapter 27, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Preface, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - List of abbreviations, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Partial printed copy of revised edition
    - Part II, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Part III, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Part IV, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Part V, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Bibliographies and transliteration charts, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Galleys
    - Galleys, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Bibliography cards
    - Bibliography cards, n.d. (Box 27, 28)
- Series III. History of Western Music
  - Work sheets
    - Carbon copy, chapter I with corrections and comments, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Chapter II, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Chapter II, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Chapter III, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Chapter III, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Chapter IV, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Chapter V, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Chapter V, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Chapter VI, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Chapter VII, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Chapter VIII, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Chapter VIII, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Chapter IX, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Chapter IX, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Chapter X, all copies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Chapter XI, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Chapter XI, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Chapter XII, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Chapter XII, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Chapter XIII, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chapter XIII, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Chapter XIV, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Chapter XIV, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 1870-1918 outline and summaries, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - 1870-1918 composer listing, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Chapter XV, notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Chapter XV, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Example list, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Illustration material, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Abbreviation and style material, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Appendix and glossary, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Partial copy with revision tabs
    - Chapter II, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Chapter III, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Chapter V, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Chapter VI, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Chapter VI, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Chapter VI, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Chapter IX, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Chapter X, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Chapter XI, footnotes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Printer's copy
    - Charts, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Pages 1-70, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Pages 71-155, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Pages 156-220, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Pages 221-305, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Pages 306-380, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Pages 381-460, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Pages 461-530, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Pages 531-600, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Pages 601-670, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Pages 671-740, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Pages 741-810, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Pages 811-881, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Pages 882-950, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Pages 951-1030, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Pages 1031-1100, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Pages 1101-1170, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Pages 1171-1250, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Pages 1251-1300, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Pages 1301-end, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous examples of music systems, etc.
    - Miscellaneous examples of music systems, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous examples of music systems (mss.), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous examples of music systems, chapter outlines, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Chapter XIV proofread by Paul H. Lang, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Lists of contents and illustrations, preface, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Chronology, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Illustrations and captions, layout and promotional material, reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Index, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Index (carbon copy), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Multilith copy
    - Chapter V, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Chapter VI, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Chapter VII, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Chapter IX, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Chapter X, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Chapter XI, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Chapter XI, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Chapter XV, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Material related to the second (1973) and third (1980) editions
    Including notes, opinions, and comments.
    - Charts (planned for first edition), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Comments and suggestions, 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Notes and articles, 1965-1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)